Leon H. Vincent Papers
Leon H. Vincent Papers
1895-1919
Vincent, Leon H. (Leon Henry), 1859-1941
4 linear ft.
Correspondence, printed material, manuscripts, miscellany from the American author and literary critic.
2620808
Biographical History
Leon H. Vincent (1859-1941) was an American author, literary critic, and lecturer. He taught English and American literature in schools and colleges across the country and wrote several books, of which the best-known is American Literary Masters, a collection of essays on noted authors.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Leon H. Vincent Papers consists of Bibliotaph material, correspondence, manuscripts, and miscellany.
Bibliotaph material consists of material related to Vincent's book The Bibliotaph and Other People, including a manuscript, a published piece in the Atlantic Monthly, and other items. Correspondence, all incoming, contains letters from Eugene Field, Edmund H. Garrett, Christopher Morley, and others. Manuscripts contains lecture notes and manuscripts of lectures, articles, and books. A small amount of Miscellany (published editions of two books by Vincent, one signed by the author) completes the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
has made a concerted effort over the years to ensure that its manuscript and rare books holdings complement each other. As a result, many of our manuscript collections are supported by books, pamphlets, serials and other items which are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection. Please be sure to search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Vincent, Leon H. (Leon Henry), 1859-1941 -- Archives.; The bibliotaph and other people.; Literature, American.; Literature -- History and criticism.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts (document genre); Clippings (information artifacts); Books.; Authors.; Critics.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Bibliotaph material
  - Bibliotaph, 1895; holograph manuscript, 42pp. (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Monthly, vol. 77, Feb 1896; includes publication of "Bibliotaph" (Box 1)
  - 4 printed pages, Bibliotaph, Keats, Gautier, Stevenson's St. Ives (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Bacon, Edwin M., 4 Mar 1899 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Mrs. Frank, 18 Aug 1915 (Box 1)
  - Field, Eugene to Dewitt Miller, 22 Jan 1892 (Box 1)
  - Ford, Worthington Chancey, undated (Box 1)
  - Garrett, Edmund H., 12 Nov 1894 (Box 1)
  - Heddrick, B.A., 20 Jan 1899; 30 Jan 1899,; 24 Oct 1899 (Box 1)
  - Mahony, Martin, 9 Dec 1891; 14 Dec 1891 (Box 1)
  - Miller, John Dewitt, 14 Jun 1904 (Box 1)
  - Milner, W.S., 20 Jul 1891 (Box 1)
  - Morley, Christopher, 23 Sep 1919 (Box 1)
  - Ritchie, Anne, 23 Jan 1916 (Box 1)
  - Scudder, H.E. (Horace Elisha), 14 Mar 1895; 23 Apr 1893 (Box 1)
  - Swift, Lindsay, 18 Jan 1897; 28 Jun 1897,; Jul 1900 (Box 1)
  - Whiting, Lilian, 12 Feb 1902; 8 Jan 1903 (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - French lectures (Box 1)
  - Great Victorian Writers, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - From book to book (Box 2)
  - Law of his nature (Box 3)
  - Novels by DeMorgan (Box 3)
  - Law of his nature and other stories (Box 3)
  - Independent Miss Dean, novel (Box 3)
  - Price of an ambition, novel (Box 3)
  - Simple pleasures of the poor (Box 4)
  - Sixteen-sixteen, short story (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray, lecture notes (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Dewitt Miller, a biographical sketch by LHV. Cambride, Riverside press, 1912, no. 19, signed by author (Box 4)
  - A few words on Robert Browning. Philadelphia, Arnold & Co., 1890, 2 copies (Box 4)